<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Savoury and Sweet Nutrition</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Savoury and Sweet Nutrition</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://savourynsweet.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Korean beef bowl</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/korean-beef-bowl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/korean-beef-bowl/</guid><description>Hi friends!
Are you missing your favourite Korean restaurant? I know I am! This Korean bibimbap bowl has been a goto of ours since we got it from a meal delivery box a few months ago. It is definitely not a traditional type of bibimbap but it&amp;rsquo;s quick and easy for weeknights.
Ingredients:
2 carrots, peeled and cut into rounds 1 zucchini, cut into rounds 1/2 lb mushrooms, sliced 1 tbsp olive oil 1 lb ground beef 2 green onions, sliced 2 tbsp soy sauce 1 tbsp sesame oil 1 tsp sugar (white, brown or honey works here) Sriracha, to taste 2 cups cooked rice, to serve Instructions:</description></item><item><title>Homemade applesauce</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/homemade-applesauce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/homemade-applesauce/</guid><description>Hi friends!
Do you love applesauce? My kids certainly do! I have tried a few recipes lately and it turns out that the old fashioned stovetop method is my favourite.
Step 1: Peel and core your apples. I tried without peeling and the texture was a little off, even after blending.
Step 2: Add apples to a saucepan with a squeeze of lemon and a few tablespoons of water. Cook on medium heat until softened (about 20 minutes).</description></item><item><title>The AATT: argula, avocado, tempeh bacon and tomato sandwich</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/the-aatt-argula-avocado-tempeh-bacon-and-tomato-sandwich/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/the-aatt-argula-avocado-tempeh-bacon-and-tomato-sandwich/</guid><description>Hi friends!
I love a good sandwich, especially if it has a ton of fillings. Of course, a BLT is one of my favourites, but rarely do I have plain lettuce hanging around. I have tried making tempeh bacon in the past, since we enjoy trying new foods and try to eat vegetarian meals more often than not. Unfortunately, my tempeh bacon was a bit of a flop. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t cut it thinly enough to get crispy.</description></item><item><title>Grain bowls</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/grain-bowls/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/grain-bowls/</guid><description>Hi friends!
Today, I want to introduce to you the meal made literally every week in this house, often more than once. It is so simple and yet always a winner with kids and adults alike.
Step 1: Pick your protein
The protein can be anything from chicken, ground meat, tempeh, eggs, edamame, chickpeas, lentils, tempeh, tofu or fish. We typically go for roasted tofu, but it&amp;rsquo;s also the perfect opportunity to use up leftover meat from any previous meals or BBQ nights.</description></item><item><title>Butternut squash: two ways</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/butternut-squash-two-ways/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/butternut-squash-two-ways/</guid><description>Hi friends!
Today we&amp;rsquo;re talking about our humble friend, the butternut squash. Like many other types of winter squash, butternut squash is harvested in the fall, but lasts a very long time after harvest. I always keep a butternut squash on hand to make some of my favourite dishes.
Butternut squash is rich in beta-carotene, which is where it gets its bright orange colour from. Beta-carotene is a precursor to vitamin A, which is known to promote eye and skin health.</description></item><item><title>Apple's frumpy friend: the Pear</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/apple-s-frumpy-friend-pear/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/apple-s-frumpy-friend-pear/</guid><description>Hi friends!
Why is it that fall is full of apple picking photos and families romping around with a wagon of pumpkins, but nary a pear in sight? I wonder if it&amp;rsquo;s because pears are best harvested before they are ripe. If you tried to eat a pear straight off the tree, then you would be met with a mouthful of hard, astringent flesh. Yuck. Also, it is definitely not the cutest fruit around.</description></item><item><title>Sourdough bread: Full of wild yeast and good bacteria</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/sourdough-fermentation-and-its-benefits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/sourdough-fermentation-and-its-benefits/</guid><description>Hi Friends!
Have you or a loved one been baking bread for the past 7 months? We certainly have! The latest family favourite is a cheese and sun-dried tomato sandwich style sourdough. We call it pizza bread and the kids love it!
Traditional sourdough bread has only three ingredients: flour, salt and starter. What is a starter, you ask? It is a live culture made of flour and water. You feed it daily to keep producing the yeast and bacteria.</description></item><item><title>Kale Caesar</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/kale-caesar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/kale-caesar/</guid><description>Hi friends,
Are you sick of kale yet? It has been much beloved by the health nuts among us for over 10 years now! From kale chips to salads to stir fries it is so very versatile. So why not mix it up by trying it in a caesar salad?
Kale Caesar, adapted slightly from Pinch of Yum:
Blend together
1/2 avocado 1/2 cup water 1/4 cup greek yogurt 1 clove garlic 2 tbsp lemon juice 1 tsp Dijon pinch of salt Toss with a kale and top with parmesan and pepitas!</description></item><item><title>Nature's candy</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/nature-s-candy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/nature-s-candy/</guid><description>Hi Friends!
My local mom&amp;rsquo;s group has been getting fruits and veggies directly from farms this summer and fall and my latest haul was a big box of pomegranates! They are perfectly ripe inside and I am obsessed. Sure, the arils are a bit of a pain to free from the fruit, but totally worth it.
What&amp;rsquo;s the best way to get the arils out, you ask? Start by cutting the pomegranate on one side and then rip it apart the rest of the way.</description></item><item><title>Meal Planning</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/meal-planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/meal-planning/</guid><description>Hi friends!
Do you ever find yourself searching your fridge and having no idea what to cook with all your groceries?!
It is so frustrating to figure out meals after shopping only to find you are missing a key ingredients or two from every recipe. So why not save yourself some time (and money) by planning before shopping? This may sound daunting, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be! Follow my fool proof steps below and you will be well on your way to an easy week of meals.</description></item><item><title>Omega-3 with a side of...mercury?</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/mercury-and-fish/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/mercury-and-fish/</guid><description>Hi friends!
Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about mercury&amp;hellip; We KNOW that fish is good for us. It has omega-3 fats, famous for brain health, reducing heart disease risk and lowering inflammation. But if it comes with a side of mercury, is it worth eating?
My best advice is to avoid certain fish which are generally HIGH in mercury. Why are they higher? Well, the bigger the fish, the more mercury can build up in the fish, which then transfers to our bodies when we eat it.</description></item><item><title>Faux meat: is it the real deal?!</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/faux-meat-is-it-the-real-deal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/faux-meat-is-it-the-real-deal/</guid><description>Hi friends!
Have you tried the new faux meat products available these days? Everyone from Target to A&amp;amp;W are getting on the bandwagon. Is it the new plant based burger that will satisfy even the beef lovers among us? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out!
I first tried an impossible burger at a cute little bistro in Los Altos and it was definitely delicious. I do like all burgers though, from salmon to beef to black bean, so I&amp;rsquo;m not the most picky.</description></item><item><title>Banana Muffins</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/banana-muffins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/banana-muffins/</guid><description>Hi friends!
Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love banana muffins? They are sweet, use up older produce and make the perfect breakfast or snack. Muffins get a bad wrap for being high in sugar and fat but they don&amp;rsquo;t need to be!
I like to add chocolate chips for a hit of sweetness and depth of flavour but feel free to omit. For my friends with egg allergies, replace the egg with a flax egg.</description></item><item><title>Biscuit pot pie</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/chicken-a-la-king/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/chicken-a-la-king/</guid><description>Hi friends!
Who is craving comfort food as the season changes from summer into autumn? There is just something about the cold weather that makes us all want something warm and creamy. This is a super unconventional pot pie recipe that my whole family loves.
Instead of the traditional pie crust, we put cheesy chive biscuits on the side and IT. IS. AWESOME.
I use this recipe to clean out my fridge and so you can easily adapt it to what you have on hand.</description></item><item><title>Simple Pita Flatbread</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/2020-10-01-simple-pita-flatbread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/2020-10-01-simple-pita-flatbread/</guid><description>Hi friends!
Are you working from home lately and feeling burnt out by the constant meal making? I am cooking for 5 people, 3 meals per day and let me tell you, I am over it some days! Today I am hooking you up with one of my fave low prep meals: pita flatbreads.
My kids love this meal because they can choose from a few toppings and who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love options?</description></item><item><title>Avocados: From Trendy to Household Staple</title><link>https://savourynsweet.com/post/avocados-not-just-for-hipsters-anymore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://savourynsweet.com/post/avocados-not-just-for-hipsters-anymore/</guid><description>Hi friends!
Today I want to talk about avocados. A few years ago, avocados were made super trendy by hot little restaurants offering avocado toast, a simple yet satisfying meal or snack. Now, avocados are still popular and it seems everyone is raving about them.
And really, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love a big bowl of guac? It is a big favourite over here, either with lunch, dinner or as an evening snack.</description></item></channel></rss>